[Music]
hello everybody and welcome to another
vintage fans and more video review
brought to you today by kitler lighting
I'd also like to welcome you into my
brand new video space there's still work
to be done here so I apologize if the
lighting or sound is a little bit off
for this video but over the past month
kiter has played a big role in making me
feel at home in these new environments
so today I'm honored to feature the
brand new Jade fan as the first video to
be filmed in this space the Jade is in
addition to the decor line of fans these
are among Ker's very best ceiling fans
so with that being said I'll jump right
into those technical details Jade is a
60-in fan available in three finish
combinations antique peor with matte
black blades which is what my fan is
brush nickel with a silver blade or oil
brushed bronze with a walnut blade
included is a dimmable LED light kit
which provides up to 800 lumens of light
output at a 3 kin color temperature so
it's a very functional light that is
still pleasing to the eye kitler also
includes a No Light cap if no light is
needed or desired also included is
kitler Standard wall mount remote
control which features three fan speeds
full range light dimming and reverse all
at the wall control inside it's a 172 by
20 mm standard AC induction motor the
blade pitch is listed at 12° all of this
combined at high speed creates an air
flow of
7,234 cubic feet of air per minute
overall pretty good for a fan of this
size and nature this model is easily one
of my favorites from kitler and overall
in The Fan industry this year I was so
drawn in by the angular blades they
almost appear to be folded like origami
it's another one of those new fans that
I feel could have existed in the modern
1990s and yet it's still so on trend for
today no kitler has a lifetime motor
warranty and 5year light kit warranty on
this fan only the best in the business
stand behind their product like that if
you haven't checked out biter I highly
encourage you to go online and look at
their catalog they have so many fans to
offer for any style or Decor many of
them highly customizable so if you're
looking for new ceiling fans you
definitely have to put kitler on your
list to look at I'm sure after all my
talking you were ready to see this fan
in action this is low speed and the
light kit is on and slightly dimmed
overall I'm not mad at this low speed
it's not too fast but it's actually
putting out decent air flow for low
speed I also have to say that I love
watching this fan in motion at a
distance the blades appear almost
weightless just a beautiful fantasy
either at standstill or in motion here
we've moved up to high speed it's maybe
not the most impressive speed wise but
the air movement is certainly apparent
we're back to low speed here's where I
will throw you to the detail clip so
that you can see this fan a little bit
closer
[Music]
[Applause]
all right so I've shut the fan down and
I will give you my final thoughts all
the fans new to the decor lineup are
really fun contemporary designs the Jade
is just one of many these are really
beautiful highquality ceiling fans
absolutely on par with the best in the
business I'd like to thank kitler
lighting for making today's video
possible and for being part of my first
video in this new space if you enjoyed
today's video be sure to let me know in
a comment down below or on any of my
social media platforms also be sure to
check out kitler on social media they
post all kinds of lighting tips and
design inspiration and you can also let
them know that you enjoyed seeing the
Jade fan here at vintage fans and more
all of those links will be down in the
description box be sure to subscribe to
this channel so that you don't miss any
of the amazing things that are going to
be happening here in this brand new
space thank you all so much for watching
today and I will see you soon